<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>workshop | Leo Y. Yang</title>
    <link>https://leoyang.org/tag/workshop/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://leoyang.org/tag/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>workshop</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2026 Leo Y. Yang</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://leoyang.org/media/icon_hu05798da5833095988f190093553a38f3_1610_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>workshop</title>
      <link>https://leoyang.org/tag/workshop/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI &#43; Social Science Workshop</title>
      <link>https://leoyang.org/talk/ai-social-science-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoyang.org/talk/ai-social-science-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I joined the &lt;strong&gt;tenth Luojia EMS Frontier Methods Bootcamp &amp;amp; AI + Social Science Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;
to exchange ideas on how generative AI reshapes empirical research in the social sciences.
Hosted by the School of Economics and Management at Wuhan University, the workshop
convened Raymond Duch, Lijia Wei, Lian Xue, Peiran Jiao, and other colleagues for a full day
of methodological training and research dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;session-highlights&#34;&gt;Session highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08:30-10:00 - Frontier methods overview.&lt;/strong&gt; Raymond Duch outlined how LLMs can act
as experimental subjects, pollsters, and market analysts, followed by Lijia Wei&amp;rsquo;s evidence on
the Matching-LLM framework for forecasting public opinion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10:20-11:50 - Research methods training.&lt;/strong&gt; Lian Xue discussed belief updating with
medical AI explanations, and Peiran Jiao linked employee voice data from Glassdoor to
firm valuation models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:50-12:35 - My presentation.&lt;/strong&gt; I presented &lt;em&gt;Predictive Power, Bias, and Trust:
Evaluating LLM-Driven Screening in FinTech Lending&lt;/em&gt;, showing how model governance and
human oversight mitigate screening bias.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14:00-16:00 - Roundtable discussion.&lt;/strong&gt; Speakers stayed on for a closed-door session to
trade implementation lessons on building trustworthy AI workflows for social-science data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These conversations fed directly into my ongoing AIECON collaborations on data-centric AI,
regulation, and human-centered evaluation of large language models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
